到目前为止，我们只考虑了透视投影的情况。这是形成的那种形象
So far we've just considered the case of perspective projection. It's the sort of image that is formed
通过简单的镜头和我们自己眼中的相同光学系统。但是这里有
by a simple lens and the same sort of optics as we have in our own eyes. But there are
许多不同种类的相机和不同种类的镜头。
many many different sorts of cameras and different sorts of lenses.
它们不一定执行透视投影。在这个特殊情况下，我们是
They don't necessarily perform perspective projection. In this particular case, we're
看着鱼眼镜头图像。这里的鱼眼镜头有一个非常广阔的领域
looking at a fish eye lens image. A fish eye lens here has got a very very wide field of
视图。如果我们看一下鱼眼镜头拍摄的图像，我们会注意到一些事情。
view. If we look at the image captured by the fish eye lens, we notice a few things.
最重要的是，我们注意到线的直线性没有保留。所以我们看到了顶部
Most importantly we note that the straightness of line is not preserved. So we see on top
在焦炭一侧的笔记本电脑，这些不再是直线。他们出现了
of the laptop on the side of the coke can, these are no longer straight lines. They appear
是曲线，因为这不是透视投影。镜片通过折射工作。
to be curves because this is not a perspective projection. Lenses work by refraction.
那就是他们弯曲穿过它们的光线。
That is they bend the rays of light that are passing through them.
我们能做到这一点的另一种方式是通过反思。我们使用曲面镜而不是镜头
Another way we can do this is by reflection. We use curved mirrors instead of lenses in
为了弯曲光线。以下是艾萨克的图画再次举例
order to bend the light rays. Here is an example again from the drawings of Isaac
牛顿的早期反射望远镜。实际上有时非常大的镜头
Newton of his early reflecting telescope. Sometimes very very big lenses are actually
由成型镜子和镜片组合而成。
made by combinations of shaped mirrors and lenses.
这些混合成像系统被称为心脏病学。这源于
These sort of hybrid imaging systems are referred to as catadioptrics. This is derived from
希腊词dioptricsforrefraction和catoptricsforreflection。
the Greek word dioptrics for refraction and catoptrics for reflection.
另一种类型的成像系统在该折反射模型上再次是全景镜头。您
Another type of imaging system again on this catadioptric model is a panoramic lens. You
在这里可以清楚地看到它。我们最底层的是相当标准的相机
can see it quite clearly here. What we have down the bottom is a fairly standard camera
在它前面有一个镜头。然后有一个拿着抛物面镜子的茎。
with a lens in front of it. And then there is a stalk which holds a parabolic mirror.
所以相机实际上是在看抛物面镜。
So the camera is actually looking at the parabolic mirror.
这种安排允许我们创建全景图。所以原始的全景，相机实际上是什么
This arrangement allows us to create panoramas. So the raw panorama, what the camera actually
看到了，这里显示在右下方。我们看到一个非常扭曲的世界观。
sees, is shown here on the bottom right. We see a very very distorted view of the world.
因为我们知道这个图像形成过程的数学，所以我们可以解开图像
Because we know the mathematics of this image formation process we can unwrap the image
这就是我们用来创建顶部显示的全景图。
and that is what we use to create the panorama shown at the top.
我们再次注意到这个全景图像是直线不被保留。
What we note with this panoramic image once again is that straight lines are not preserved.
他们似乎非常严重扭曲。
They appear to be very very seriously distorted.